

Resume
Full Stack Developer | Software
Developer

Personal details

George O

George Ochieng' Outa



george.jarviz@gmail.com



+254 (0) 700 613065



1845 40100 Kisumu



outafrica.me



linkedin.com/in/george-outa



github.com/outafrica

Skills

Agile Methodologies	••••
Laravel(PHP)	••••
VueJs	••••
Tailwind	••••
Flutter	••••
API integrations	••••
MySQL/PostgresSQL/Mo ngoDB/MariaDB	••••
Test Driven	••••

Development (TDD

PHPUnit/Pest)

Problem Solver

Career Profile

As a highly skilled and successful leader with seven years comprehensive experience in software development principles, I possess a wide range of knowledge and skills that allow me to contribute toward the success of projects I undertake. Throughout my career, I have been acknowledged as a solution-focused professional with the ability to design and develop innovative applications using advanced technologies. I have advanced proficiencies in Laravel(PHP), VueJs, Flutter, and excellent customer service skills. I also have a solid foundation in MySQL, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, and Node.JS. My attention to detail, organizational skills and strong communication have allowed me to lead software development teams and ensure the success of each project assigned to me.

Employment

Feb 2022 - Sep 2022

Full Stack Developer

International Development Law Organization, Nairobi

Worked as a consultant for the Judiciary of Kenya through the International Development Law Organization (IDLO).

Key Responsibilities:

- Collected user requirements based on newly realized features from emerging problems.
- Implemented new features in applications based on gathered requirements after objectoriented analysis.
- Analyzed issues and made improvements to the project's existing features and components.
- Coordinated with other team members for development of portal solutions to support API.
- Developed technical documentation in coordination with software engineering teams.
- Completed all the duties efficiently & timely as issued by the team lead.

Jun 2021 - Sep 2022

Lead Mobile(Flutter) Developer

:Brij Innovation Group, Nairobi

A modern, simple and secure way to make instant payments, send and receive money, pay bills, and shop across Africa.

Key Responsibilities:

- Implemented UI and UXs from design team.
- Implemented unit, widget & integration tests using Mockito.
- Performed code reviews and mentored my team by providing support as well learning from them through the developmental and career journey.
- Published apps on Android Playstore, and IOS Appstore/TestFlight.

Aug 2020 - Feb 2021

Full Stack Developer

International Development Law Organization, Nairobi

Worked as a consultant for the Judiciary of Kenya through the International Development Law Organization (IDLO).

Key Responsibilities:

• Gathered user requirements based on new

Communicator	••••
Team Player	••••
GIT	••••
CI/CD	••••
DevOps (DigitalOcean/AWS)	••••
JIRA	••••
Sentry	••••
C++	••••
Languages —	
English	••••
Kiswahli	••••
Hobbies ——	

Chess

Basketball

Cooking

Reading novels

features realized from arising issues.

- Developed new features based on gathered requirements and provided improvements on existing code components and features of applications.
- Implemented methods for identifying and resolving technical issues.
- Provided code documentation and other application inputs to technical documents.

Jan 2020 - Mar 2020

Full Stack Developer

Enzihealth Limited, Nairobi

A health focused ecosystem that allow users to get medical attention at the comfort of their spaces even from work place, home and outdoors.

Key Responsibilities:

- Implemented APIs to support registration and hail applications using <u>Africa's talking</u> via USSD.
- Implemented <u>Safaricom Mpesa APIs</u> to implement APIs that handle payment requests.
- Performed unit tests to validate application components and debugged code based on unit tests results.
- Implemented a mobile version of the app using flutter to enable registration, hailing requests and payment processing.
- Deployed project to production.

Oct 2017 - Oct 2021

Full Stack Developer

Uhired Limited, Nairobi

A job marketing and recruitment service provider.

Key Responsibilities:

- Implemented and wrote test for new and existing features.
- Provided technical support to the team members and handled client issues as arise.
- Upgrading the project from Laravel 4.2 to Laravel 7.0
- Maintained the project by fixing bugs & documenting code.
- Deployed code to production.

Education

May 2013 - Sep 2018

Bachelor of Science - Computer Science

University of Nairobi, Nairobi

Graduated from University of Nairobi – Nairobi, Kenya

BSc. Computer Science.

Cluster; Upper Second-Class Honors

Feb 2008 - Nov 2011

Kenya Certificate of Secondary Education (KCSE) O-level

Maranda Boys High School, Bondo

References

Mr. Leonard Korir - Lead Technology Manager Brij Innovation Group, Nairobi

+254 728 355429, lkorir@bridgeinnovation.io

Mr. Steven Ikileng - A/g. ICT Director Judiciary of Kenya, Nairobi +254 722 980 453, steven.ikileng@court.go.ke

Mrs. Grace Nyagaya - Systems Administrator KEMRI/CDC at CGHR, Kisumu +254 722 941 721, gnyagaya@kemricdc.org